<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>authorization on Blog</title>
    <link>https://ltanguy.github.io/tags/authorization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in authorization on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 11:15:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://ltanguy.github.io/tags/authorization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk &amp; Articles Log</title>
      <link>https://ltanguy.github.io/talk-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:41:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ltanguy.github.io/talk-log/</guid>
      <description>DevOps - Practices  Sandeep Pokkunuri • Ensuring Rollback Safety During Deployments (Amazon Builders&amp;rsquo; Library)  Engineering culture  Pat Kua • Secrets of a Strong Engineering Culture (QCon 2020)  Software Engineering - Monoliths and Micro-services   Sam Newman • Monolith Decomposition Patterns (QCon 2020)
  Matt Heath • Building a Bank with Go (QCon 2017)
  Jason Maude • Building a Reliable Cloud-Based Bank in Java (QCon 2017)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ltanguy.github.io/dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 12:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ltanguy.github.io/dev/</guid>
      <description>Ident.io SAML A developer-friendly SAML 2.0 API written in Java.
Github Project
Ident.io Server A cloud-native authentication and federation server
Github Project Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Cloud Impressions</title>
      <link>https://ltanguy.github.io/2020/05/oracle-cloud-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:56:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ltanguy.github.io/2020/05/oracle-cloud-impressions/</guid>
      <description>After hearing the news that Zoom was moving part of its infrastructure to Oracle Cloud and reading a few articles on that matter, I was curious to see with my own eyes what Oracle&amp;rsquo;s offer looked like.
Please note that I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with (but not affiliated to) AWS, much less with Azure or GCP, so this article is in no way exhaustive nor a comprehensive benchmark of the cloud market. I may be a little biased, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep it to a minimum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ltanguy.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 15:57:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ltanguy.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I speak mostly about software engineering, architecture, security, cloud infrastructure and sometimes tech culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authorization with TLS Mutual Authentication</title>
      <link>https://ltanguy.github.io/2020/05/tls-ma-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 11:15:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ltanguy.github.io/2020/05/tls-ma-authorization/</guid>
      <description>TLS Mutual Authentication (TLS MA or more commonly nowadays mTLS) is increasingly being leveraged for securing links between applications (see the section of Istio&amp;rsquo;s documentation on security as an example).
It provides a much more robust and secure solution than static shared credentials:
 Shared credentials are susceptible to brute-force attacks. Shared credentials should be periodically rotated. In practice, this is almost never the case as the process is particularly painful and implies the rotation of the credentials at the server and client level simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
